John Henry is a animation, drama, family film directed by Mark Henn.
The story of the legendary steel-driving folk hero born with a hammer in his hands,
who pitted his strength against a mighty railroad-building machine.
Polly / Narrator (voice), played by Alfre Woodard.
MacTavish (voice), played by Tim Hodge.
John Henry (voice), played by Geoffrey Jones.
Thomas (voice), played by Dave Murray.
Singing Voice of Polly (voice), played by Carrie Harrington.
John Henry is an animation short film from Walt Disney Animation
Studios directed by Mark Henn, released on October 30, 2000.
The short is based on African American folk hero John Henry.
The film explores themes of legend, tall tale, short film.
The tone is emotional.